Scientists are trying to make your
organs young again, and they just
started their first [music] human
clinical trial focusing on the cells in
your eye. When you're a little embryo,
your cells start out as unspecialized
stem cells, but as they grow, they morph
into the ones with specialized jobs. And
then as you age, they can break down and
die, which in your eyes can cause
blindness. So, previous studies have
shown that by adding specific proteins
to a cell, you can get it to act like a
stem cell and then coax it into a
totally different kind of cell, which is
crazy. But, this trial is trying to take
the neurons in your eye and turn back
the clock and stop them just before they
turn into stem cells by carefully adding
just some of those proteins and then
coaxing them back into healthy
functioning neurons. But, what seems
really clever is these proteins only
work when activated by a specific
antibiotic. So, if something goes wrong,
your doctors can stop the antibiotic and
your eye goes back to normal. The first
patient is already being treated. So, to
see what happens, subscribe.